[Hasegawa accidentally performed a Kinniku Buster on a girl and has been arrested on molestation charges.]
[Incidentally, this year 2008 marks the 29th year of Ultimate Muscle's serialization.]
(長谷川)ﾊﾂ… あの…➡
Hatsu, um...
ｵﾚたち やり直さ…｡
Can you and I start over...?
Hatsu-san...
(破牙)ﾊﾂさん｡
I'm sorry, I'll call you later.
(ﾊﾂ)ごめん…｡ あとで かけ直す｡
(女性)ｷｬｰｯ！ 痴漢よ～!!
(長谷川)あれ？
Pervert!
It's the Kinniku Buster! Kinniku Buster!
[Note: Kinnikuman's trademark attack and one of 48 killer moves. From Ultimate Muscle.]
(女性)ｷﾝ肉ﾊﾞｽﾀｰよ！
ｷﾝ肉ﾊﾞｽﾀｰだわ!!
はっ…！
I will be the prosecutor in the court of law where you will be tried in two days.
(破牙)私…
２日後に あなたが立たされる➡
白洲の場にて 検事を務めます➡
破牙と 申します｡
My name is Haga.
(ﾊｲｼﾞ)ﾊﾊﾊﾊ！ ﾍﾟｰﾀｰ！
Peter!
《ﾊｲｼﾞ～!!》
Heidi!
We will now start the trial for the Edo Line Kinniku Buster molestation case.
(奉行)これより➡
大江戸線 ｷﾝ肉ﾊﾞｽﾀｰ痴漢事件の
詮議を 行う｡
(銀時)あ～ すんませ～ん！
遅れました～！
Sorry, I'm late!
弁護士の 坂田で～す！
I'm the attorney, Sakata.
よろしく お願いしま～す｡
Nice to meet you.
《…銀さん!?》
Gin-san?
それでは 詮議 開始！
We will now start the trial.
["Men, Be A Madao"]
(破牙)被告人 長谷川 泰三は➡
On February 21st at 7:25, the defendant Taizo Hasegawa,
２月21日 ７時25分➡
かぶき町駅ﾎｰﾑにて➡
forcefully grabbed the hand of the victim, Ms. A, on the platform at Kabukicho station
被害者Ａ子さんの手を
無理やり 握り➡
and dragged her down into the railway.
線路下まで 引きずり下ろし➡
He is suspected of performing a Kinniku Buster in front of everyone.
公衆の面前で ｷﾝ肉ﾊﾞｽﾀｰをかけた
疑いが かけられております｡
This is clearly an act of molestation and assault.
(破牙)これは 明らかに
痴漢行為であり 暴行罪➡
And depending on the circumstances, it may even be considered attempted murder.
場合によっては 殺人未遂などの
罪に 当たると思われます｡
ﾎｰﾑにて 多くの人々が
被告人の犯行を 目撃しています｡
Many people on the platform witnessed the defendant's actions.
詮議に かけるまでもなく
被告人は 有罪かと…｡
Without even having to examine him, it is clear that the defendant is guilty.
異議あり！
(奉行)坂田弁護人｡
Objection!
Defense Attorney Sakata.
被告人が 被害者 女性に
ｷﾝ肉ﾊﾞｽﾀｰをかけたのは 事実です｡
It is true that the defendant performed a Kinniku Buster on the victim.
[Kinniku Buster Molestation Case - Exhibit 1]
[Note: Image is a spoof of the first appearance of Kinniku Buster in Ultimate Muscle.]
しかし
これが 故意であるものなのか➡
However whether he did this with the intent to molest
さらに言えば 痴漢を目的として
行われたことで あるのかは➡
is still questionable.
甚だ 疑問であります！
この事件は
事故である可能性が 高い｡
There is a strong possibility that this incident was an accident.
被告人は
ﾎｰﾑの下に 落下しそうになり➡
The defendant almost fell off the platform and
accidentally performed a Kinniku Buster on the girl.
偶発的に 女性に ｷﾝ肉ﾊﾞｽﾀｰを
かけてしまったと思われます｡
Therefore, I plead the defendant is not guilty.
よって 私は…➡
被告人の無罪を 主張します！
《銀さ～ん！
Gin-san!
食らいついてやがる！
He's laying into him.
He's totally laying into Haga!
ｱｲﾂ…
破牙に 食らいついてやがる！》
偶発的？
Accidentally?
Do you seriously think a complicated move like the Kinniku Buster
ｷﾝ肉ﾊﾞｽﾀｰなどという 複雑な技が➡
can be performed accidentally?
偶然 かけられると
お思いですか？
ｷﾝ肉ﾏﾝが あの技を編み出すのに
どれだけ 苦労したか…｡
Apparently, the defense is unaware of how hard Kinnikuman
had to work to come up with that move.
弁護人は
わかっていないようですね…｡
Objection!
異議あり！
そもそも ｷﾝ肉ﾊﾞｽﾀｰという技を➡
In the first place, it's wrong to equate the Kinniku Buster as an act of molestation.
痴漢行為とすること自体が
誤りです｡
あれは ｷﾝ肉ﾏﾝが 残虐超人を
倒すために 使用した技です｡
The Kinniku Buster was used by Kinnikuman to destroy the evil super humans.
ｷﾝ肉ﾏﾝが ごつい超人相手に➡
I cannot imagine that Kinnikuman had perverted intentions
いやらしい目的で
使用していたとは➡
when using this move against the giant super humans.
考えられません！ そもそも！
Besides...
被告人が かけた技は
ｷﾝ肉ﾊﾞｽﾀｰじゃない｡
The move performed by the defendant is not the Kinniku Buster.
The Kinniku Buster is called that because it's done by Kinnikuman.
ｷﾝ肉ﾊﾞｽﾀｰは ｷﾝ肉ﾏﾝが かけるから
ｷﾝ肉ﾊﾞｽﾀｰなのであって➡
被告人
長谷川 泰三が かけた技は…➡
The correct name for the move performed by the defendant, Taizo Hasegawa,
should be the Hasegawa Buster.
長谷川ﾊﾞｽﾀｰ というのが 正しい！
Objection!
異議あり！ ｷﾝ肉ﾊﾞｽﾀｰは➡
The Kinniku Buster got its name when Kinnikuman perfected it.
ｷﾝ肉ﾏﾝが 完成させた時点で
ｷﾝ肉ﾊﾞｽﾀｰなのであり➡
以後 誰が使ったとしても
ｷﾝ肉ﾊﾞｽﾀｰと呼ぶのが 正しい｡
Therefore, no matter who uses it, it should still be called the Kinniku Buster.
Objection!
異議あり!!
The Kinniku Buster is one of 48 deadly moves that Prince Kamehame taught Kinnikuman.
ｷﾝ肉ﾊﾞｽﾀｰは ｷﾝ肉ﾏﾝが
ﾌﾟﾘﾝｽｶﾒﾊﾒから伝授された➡
48の必殺技の１つであり➡
ｷﾝ肉ﾏﾝは 開発していません｡
Kinnikuman was not the one who came up with it.
When others used the move, the users' name preceded the move.
つまり 使用者の名前が
頭に くるのであり➡
実際 ｱｼｭﾗﾏﾝが使った際は➡
For example, when Ashuraman used this move, it was called the Ashura Buster.
ｱｼｭﾗﾊﾞｽﾀｰ と 呼称されていました｡
弁護人の異議を 認める！
(破牙)ｸｯ…！
I will allow the objection.
Damn.
以後 ｷﾝ肉ﾊﾞｽﾀｰは
長谷川ﾊﾞｽﾀｰ と 呼称するように｡
From here on, the Kinniku Buster will be called the Hasegawa Buster.
《す… すげえ～！
A-Amazing!
まったく
意味のない やりとりだが➡
It was a totally meaningless exchange,
ﾌﾟﾛ相手に
完全に 優位に立っている！
yet he managed to win against a professional.
As expected from a guy who can talk himself out of anything!
さすがは
口先から 生まれてきた男！
Look how cool he looks.
なんて 憎たらしい顔してんだ！
確かに ｱｲﾂが 口ｹﾞﾝｶで
負けているところなんて➡
Now that I think about it, I don't think I've ever seen him lose an argument.
見たことがねえ！ いける！
[As Expected]
[Note: The first character actually says 'sugar' and is not the correct kanji to use for this word.]
This may just work.
ﾔﾂなら いけるかもしれない！》
He may be able to get the job done for me.
お奉行｡ ﾌﾟﾘﾝｽｶﾒﾊﾒから 伝授された
殺人技を➡
Your honor.
He must have had unshakeable evidence for him to say a killer move
taught by Prince Kamehame was used for molestation.
痴漢行為などと
こじつけたからには➡
よほどの 確固たる証拠が
あったんでしょうね｡
I'd like for him to present that evidence.
I ask Prosecutor Haga to show us the evidence.
その証拠を
明確に 示していただきたい｡
破牙検事に
証拠品の提出を 求めます！
《長谷川:いけ～！ 銀さ～ん!!》
Go! Gin-san!
破牙検事 証拠を示したまえ｡
Prosecutor Haga, present the evidence.
んっ？ どうしたの？
Hm? What's wrong?
まさか
証拠もないのに 決めつけてたの？
Don't tell me you came to this conclusion without any evidence?
So these are false accusations?
冤罪事件だね こりゃ｡
被告人の部屋を 調べた結果…➡
When we searched the defendant's room,
このようなものが 出てきました｡
we found these.
((女の子:あは～ん｡ うふ～ん｡
いや～ん！))
I didn't want to bring out such offensive trash and violate the sanctity of the court, but...
(破牙)このような 下品なもの…➡
神聖な詮議の場で
出したくなかったのですが…｡
Yikes...
《うわっ！ ぐあぁぁ～っ!!
[Note: Book Off is a popular Japanese used books chain that buys books from its customers and resells.]
I should have sold'em to Book Off a long time ago!
さっさと ﾌﾞｯｸｵﾌﾞに
売り飛ばすべきだった～!!》
♪♪～
(ﾊｲｼﾞ)ﾖｰｾﾞﾌ～！
Joseph!
ﾖｰｾﾞﾌ… よくも
谷に 落としてくれたな～！
Joseph... How dare you kick me into the ravine.
Heidi...
ﾊｲｼﾞ～!!
Heidi came back from the depths of hell!
(長谷川)ﾊｲｼﾞが
地獄の底から よみがえった～!!
You can join me too. Joseph!
(ﾊｲｼﾞ)お前も こっち来～い｡
ﾖｰｾﾞﾌ～!!))
《長谷川:銀さ～ん 早く！
Gin-san! Hurry... Hurry and do something.
早く なんとかしてくれ～!!》
He had about thirty of them.
(破牙)所持数 およそ30枚｡
Some were even about molestation.
なかには 痴漢ものも ありました｡
被告人の異常なまでの
性への執着が➡
I think you can now see the defendant's abnormal obsession with sex.
これで わかっていただけたかと
思いますが…｡
《長谷川:銀さん！ お前 何枚か
貸してやっただろうがぁ！》
[Edo Video Mature Audience]
[Sales or rental to those under 18 years of age is prohibited.]
Gin-san!
I lent you a few of those, didn't I?
異議あり!!
破牙検事が示す これらのものは➡
Objection! These items presented by Prosecutor Haga are insufficient as evidence.
証拠品としては 不十分です！
中を改めさせてください！
Allow me to check what's on the disc.
ﾋﾞﾃﾞｵの再生を要求します！
Please play the videos.
《長谷川:お前 ただ
見たいだけだろうがぁぁ!!》
You just wanna watch them!
異議あり！ お奉行
弁護人の要求は➡
Objection! Your honor, the request by the defense is irrelevant to this case.
本件から逸脱しています｡
There's no reason to check what's on the discs.
中身など確認しても
意味がありません｡
Objection overruled.
検事の意見を却下！
弁護人の要求を認める｡
I will allow the request of the defense.
ﾋﾞﾃﾞｵを再生しなさい｡
Please play the discs.
《長谷川:お前も見たいんかい！
You just wanna watch them too?!
おい これ 何の裁判だよ！
なんだよ これ！
Hey, what kind of a trial is this anyway?
What's going on? What the hell...?
えぇ？ いったい 何が…》
Objection!
異議あり！
《長谷川:誰に対してだぁ!?》
Who are you objecting to?
お奉行！ 今のところ
巻き戻しを要求します！
Your honor, please rewind that section.
尻を ぶっ叩いてるところから!!
Back to the part with the spanking.
《長谷川:どんな異議だぁ!?》
What kind of objection is this?!
Objection! This is completely senseless.
異議あり！
これ以上は 無意味です｡
詮議に戻りましょう！
Let's get back to the trial.
検事の異議は 却下！
Objection overruled.
Rewind and play it in slow motion.
巻き戻して ｽﾛｰ再生しなさい｡
《長谷川:お奉行!!
Your honor!!
Hurry up or Heidi will...!
早くしねえと ﾊｲｼﾞがぁぁ!!》
死ね～っ!!
(銃声)
Die!
(ﾊｲｼﾞ)ｵﾝｼﾞ～！
Grandpa!
この ｸｿ犬が！ ﾊｲｼﾞ 待ってろ～！
You damn dog! Heidi, hang in there.
《おじいさんまでが ｵﾚを
谷底に落とそうとしているぅ!!
Even the old man's trying to drop me into the ravine.
銀さん もう限界だよ～!!》
Gin-san!
I'm at my limit!
弁護人 これらの証拠に対し
ぬしの意見が聞きたい｡
Counsel, I would like to hear your opinion about the evidence presented.
問題ないでしょう｡
Why of course.
男性なら 誰でも異性に
興味があるのは 当たり前のこと｡
As a man, it's only natural to be interested in the opposite sex.
被告人のｺﾚｸｼｮﾝは 一般的な
成人男子の嗜好を越える➡
I think the defendant's collection is no more than what an average healthy male possesses.
ﾚﾍﾞﾙでは ないと思います｡
むしろ こういうものを
持ってないほうが異常でしょう｡
On the contrary, I think it's abnormal to not own these kinds of videos.
それとも 破牙さん…
あなたは こういうものを➡
Or are you telling me, Haga-san, that you do not own a single video like these?
１本も持っていないんですか？
しかし 30本は 一般的にみても
多いと思われます｡
Yes, but in general, I think thirty discs are too many.
お奉行… お奉行の意見を
お聞かせ願いたい｡
Your honor. I would like to hear your take on this matter.
被告人のｺﾚｸｼｮﾝは
証拠不十分とみなす！
The defendant's collection is not enough to be treated as evidence.
《長谷川:30本以上 持ってるよ！
お奉行!!》
You've got more than thirty discs, your honor?!
ああっ！
あっ 間違えた！
(銃声)
ごめん ﾊｲｼﾞ！
Oops, I missed. Sorry, Heidi.
じじい！ ﾃﾒｴ～!!
ﾊｲｼﾞがぁ！ しめた ﾁｬﾝｽだ！
You geezer...bastard!
Heidi!
Good, this is my chance. Gin-san, keep going.
銀さん たたみかけろ！
破牙検事 どうやら あなたは
さしたる証拠もなく➡
Prosecutor Haga...
It looks like you've determined the defendant's guilt without any substantial evidence.
被告人を犯人と決めつけて…｡
(破牙)ちょっと待った！
Hold on.
私 今回の詮議を前に➡
Prior to today's trial, I ran a background check on the defendant.
被告人の身辺調査を
させてもらったんですが➡
今までの経歴
友人関係まで調べた結果➡
I checked his past history and relationships and discovered something very interesting.
おもしろいことがわかりましてね｡
異議あり！
お奉行 検事は 明らかに➡
Objection!
Your honor, the prosecutor is clearly trying to change the subject.
話を そらそうとしています｡
弁護人の異議を却下します！
Objection overruled.
破牙検事 続けなさい｡
Prosecutor Haga, please continue.
３週前の 『銀魂』の放送を
ご覧いただけますか？
Please take a look at the previous GinTama episode.
Haga-kun, stop this futile battle.
破牙く～ん
悪あがきは よしたまえ｡
観そこなったなら ちゃんと
DVDを買ってくれないと➡
If you missed the last episode, then just buy the DVD or what will happen to Aniplex?
[Note: Aniplex is a Japanese music and anime production and distribution enterprise.]
ｱﾆﾌﾟﾚｯｸｽが…｡
(破牙)こちらに
着替えをする女性を➡
There's a man looking in on a girl changing.
覗く男が映ってるんですが…
どこかで見たことありませんか？
Does he look familiar?
That's against the rules!
《長谷川:それ 反則だろ～!!》
♪♪～
(破牙)そこにいる 坂田弁護士は
３週間前➡
Three weeks ago, the attorney, Mr. Sakata,
was questioned by police on charges of peeping into a girl's room while she was changing.
着替えをする女性を
覗いていた疑いで➡
同心から
職質を受けているのです｡
証拠不十分で 厳重注意で
事は 済んだようですが➡
Due to a lack of evidence he was let go with a stern warning,
果たして 被告人の痴漢容疑を
弁護する資格があるのかどうか？
but can someone like that be qualified to defend the molestation charges of his client?
I still question that. How do you all feel, ladies and gentlemen of the court?
はなはだ 私は 疑問ですな｡
どうですか？ 傍聴席の皆さん｡
(ざわめき)
Go home, pervert attorney!
帰りやがれ ｴﾛ弁護士がっ!!
(傍聴人)この 痴漢ｺﾝﾋﾞが！
A pair of perverts! Throw both of them in the slammer!
２人とも まとめて 牢に
ぶち込まれっちまいやがれ!!
静粛に！ 者ども 静粛にせい！
Silence!
Silence in the court.
破牙検事
傍聴席を あおらぬように｡
Prosecutor Haga! Do not incite the audience!
《破牙ぁ！ なんて野郎だ！
ｵﾚだけじゃなく➡
Haga! What an asshole!
Not only did he check up on me, but on Gin-san too?
銀さんのことまで
調査済みだったとは…➡
これが ﾌﾟﾛの検事の力！
So this is the power of a true professional prosecutor.
これじゃ ｵﾚたちに勝ち目は…》
How can we win against this?
We don't have a chance in hell!
万に一つもねえぇぇ～!!
うおっ！
(ﾊｲｼﾞ)ﾖｰｾﾞﾌ～ ﾕｷちゃ～ん！
こっちへ おいで～！
Joseph, Yuki-chan, come here.
[Note: Yuki is a goat from the anime version of Heidi. Gintoki is dressed up as him.]
あ… 何!?
Huh? What?
(ﾊｲｼﾞの うなり声)
おっ… おわっ ﾊｲｼﾞ～!!
Heidi!!
(ﾊｲｼﾞ)こっちへ おいで～え！
Come here...
《長谷川:いや… あれは
もはや ﾊｲｼﾞじゃない！
No, this isn't Heidi anymore.
闇に呑まれ 異形と化したか！
Has she changed into something worse after being swallowed up by the abyss?
あれに呑まれれば ｵﾚたちに
一生 幸せは来ないぞ！
If that swallows us up, then we'll never find happiness.
銀さん なんとかしろ～！》
Gin-san, do something.
いっ 異議あり！
O...Objection!
私のことは
今回のこととは関係ない！
What happened to me has nothing to do with this case.
第一 あれは 公園で休んでいた
私の視界に たまたま➡
Besides, I was just resting in the park when that girl just happened to come into my view.
女性が入ってきただけの話！
もう 誤解は 解けています！
That misunderstanding has already been cleared up.
Objection! It has everything to do with this.
異議あり！
大いに関係ありますな！
痴漢に 痴漢の弁護が
務まるとお思いか！
Do you think a pervert can defend another pervert?
What this shows is that the two of them were part of some sexually perverted community.
何よりも この事実は➡
彼らの間に 変態的ｺﾐｭﾆﾃｨが
築かれていたことを➡
示しています！
I'm telling you, I wasn't peeping!
だ～か～ら～！ ｵﾚは
覗きなんてしてねえって➡
言ってんだろうが！
ｺｲﾂと一緒にすんじゃねえ！
Don't put me in the same category as this guy.
殺すぞ ｺﾗｯ！ …あっ｡
I'm gonna kill you!!
お奉行 聞きましたか？
Your honor! Did you hear that?
The defense just admitted to the defendant's charges.
今 弁護人は 被告人の容疑を
みずから認めました！
(悲鳴)
Damn.
What are you saying?
(長谷川)何言っちゃってんだよ
お前は！
ｵﾚの弁護人だろうが！
You're supposed to be defending me, right?
いっ… 異議あり！
間違えました!!
O-Objection! I made a mistake.
今のは 口が滑りました！
つい 本音が…｡
That was a slip of the tongue.
The truth slipped out...
(長谷川)おい！ ﾃﾒｴは やっぱ➡
Come on! So you really believe I committed a lewd act?!
ｵﾚが痴漢やったと思ってんのか！
Shut up! Now that it's down to this, all I can think about is saving myself.
うるせえっ！
事ここまでに及ぶと➡
もはや 自分が助かるだけで
精一杯だ！
ｼｬﾄﾙは 切り離し作業に移ります！
The shuttle will now separate and take off on its own.
ふざけるな！ こうなったら
ﾃﾒｴも道連れだ！
Don't give me that.
I'm taking you down with me now!
ﾌﾌｯ… 勝負ありました｡
The verdict is in.
♪♪～
お奉行 これ以上の詮議は
時間のﾑﾀﾞかと｡
Your honor, further examination would only be a waste of time.
被告人 長谷川 泰三に
厳正なるお裁きを｡
I ask you to hand down a severe punishment to the defendant, Taizo Hasegawa.
(奉行)うむ…｡
Hm...
ちょっと待ったぁ！
Just a minute!
弁護人の非で 私の罪が
決まるというのなら➡
If the defense's mistake determines my guilt,
検事の非で 私は
無罪になるんでしょうか｡
then will the prosecutor's mistake determine my innocence?
だったら あるぞ ここに！
If that's the case, then here it is.
破牙検事の秘密が！
Prosecutor Haga's secret!!
Prosecutor Haga and my wife...
破牙検事は 私の…｡
長谷川 泰三の妻…｡
別居中の妻と
親しい仲にあります！
He's in a relationship with my separated wife.
検事は 私の妻と
一緒になりたいばかりに➡
In hopes of getting together with my wife, he offered me an unlawful deal.
私に不正の取引を
もちかけてきました！
離婚届に判を押せば
詮議に勝たせてやる と！
He said if I put my seal on the divorce papers, he'd let me win this trial.
長谷川さん…｡
いいんだ…｡
Hasegawa-san...
It's okay...
ｵﾚが 恥かいて ﾔﾂに勝てるなら➡
If I can win by humiliating myself...
ｵﾚが恥かいて ﾊﾂを救えるなら…｡
If I can save Hatsu by humiliating myself, then I'll do it.
それでいい…｡
Prosecutor Haga, is what the defendant just said true?
破牙検事… 今の被告人の証言は➡
誠か？
事実です｡
It's true.
(どよめき)
ただし 彼の妻と
個人的なつきあいが➡
But only up to the part where he said I have a relationship with his wife.
あるというところまでです｡
不正の取引があったというのは
事実ではありません｡
It's not true that I offered him an unlawful deal.
被告人が言っていることは
事実無根のでっちあげです｡
What the defendant is saying is completely fictitious.
なに言ってやがる！
ｵﾚは 実際 お前に…｡
What are you saying?
You told me...
Do you have proof?
(破牙)証拠はあるのですか？
私とあなたの間に
不正な取引があったという証拠｡
Proof that an unlawful deal was made between you and me.
あるなら 今 ここで
示してください｡
If you have that proof, let's see it right now.
うぅ…｡
Objection!
異議あり！ たとえ
不正の事実が➡
Even if he may not be able to prove that an unlawful deal existed between the two of you, this picture...
確かめられなくとも この写真は
ｱﾝﾀが 私的理由で➡
...should serve as proof that you tried to convict the defendant based on personal reasons.
被告人を有罪に
陥れようとしていた➡
証拠になるはずだ！
それは被告人も同じことです｡
But the same can be said for the defendant...
その写真は 被告人が私的理由…｡
That picture can serve as evidence that the defendant acted on personal reasons.
つまり 妻を取られたという
個人的怨恨から➡
It can be argued that he made up unfounded lies...
私を陥れようと
根も葉もない虚言を➡
from a grudge held against the prosecutor for stealing his wife.
繰り返している証拠にも
なりえます｡
(破牙)それだけではない！
Not only that.
見つけた～！
I found you!!
(破牙)妻に逃げられ
仕事もうまくいかず➡
With his wife deserting him and his work not going well,
性的に… いや失礼…
精神的に満たされなかった➡
...the defendant was unable to find sexual... I mean, mental satisfaction...
被告人が 痴漢などという
破廉恥な行為によって➡
And so he fulfilled himself by committing lewd sexual acts.
充足を得ていた…｡
Doesn't this prove that?
Gin-san!
その何よりの証拠と
なりえるのではないでしょうか｡
この写真は 彼が負け犬だという
何よりの証拠です！
This picture is proof that he is a doggone loser.
破牙検事 言葉を慎みなさい！
Prosecutor Haga, watch what you say.
ﾌﾌﾌ… 負け犬ではなく
何と呼べと？
If I can't call him a doggone loser, then what do you want me to call him?
ﾊﾊﾊ… ぴったりではないですか
彼に！
It's the perfect name for him.
私がﾊﾂ殿を手に入れるために
彼を陥れようとしていた？
I was trying to entrap him so I could make Hatsu-dono mine?
ﾊﾊ… ﾊﾞｶな！ こんな負け犬を➡
That's ridiculous!
Do you think Hatsu-dono is still in love with a doggone loser like him?
ﾊﾂ殿が まだ愛していると
お思いか？
こんな負け犬を陥れるために➡
Do you think I would actually go out of my way to entrap a doggone loser like him?
私が わざわざ動くとお思いか？
そんな必要はない！
なぜなら 私とﾊﾂ殿は➡
There's no need for that.
Because Hatsu-dono and I already love each other!
すでに愛し合っているのだから！
お奉行！ もはや詮議は必要なし｡
Your honor! There's no need to continue with the trial.
この負け犬にふさわしき裁きを！
Hand down your sentence that befits this doggone loser.
うむ…｡
(奉行)被告人 弁護人
共に 異議はあるか？
Defense, Prosecution.
Do either of you have any objections?
(長谷川)うぉっ… いっ 異議…！
O-Objection!
いいえ ありません… ｹﾞｯﾌﾟ｡
No objections.
異議あ～り！
Objection!
What's this?
《これは… 銀さん？ いや…》
Gin-san...
Clara!!
[Note: Gintoki is dressed up as Clara from the anime version of Heidi.]
《長谷川:ｸﾗﾗ！ ｸﾗﾗが立っ…
飛んだ～っ！》
Clara rises... No, flies!!
検事！ ｱﾝﾀ 今 言ったよな！
Prosecutor! You just said, "we love each other..."
私たちは 愛し合っていると！
もう詮議の必要はねえと！
And "there's no need to continue with the trial."
つまり ﾃﾒｴの潔白を
証明できるものは➡
In other words, the only thing that proves your innocence is that thing you call love.
その愛ってﾔﾂだけっつうことだな｡
だったら
見せてもらおうじゃねえか！
If that's the case, then let's see it.
Let's see this love of yours.
ﾃﾒｴの愛ってﾔﾂを！
(どよめき)
Your honor!
(新八)お奉行！ これが破牙検事の
愛ってﾔﾂでございます！
This is what Prosecutor Haga calls love.
そこの破牙検事は
被告人 長谷川 泰三の妻の他に➡
We found that Prosecutor Haga is involved with many women
複数の女性と
親しい関係であることが➡
besides the defendant Taizo Hasegawa's wife.
調べた結果 わかりました！
しかも 相手は 金持ちばかり！
And not only that, they're all wealthy.
さらに調べた結果 破牙検事は…｡
Upon further investigation, Prosecutor Haga is...
Order the outsiders to leave.
(破牙)
部外者を退場させてください！
異議あり！ 彼らは
私が連れてきた重要参考人です!!
Objection! I brought these people down as material witnesses!
証言台に立たせてください！
Please let them take the stand.
弁護人の異議を認める！
I will allow it.
(神楽)えぇ!?
おい！ 愛を証拠とする？
Huh? What's that? Love is your proof?
ずいぶんと大勢に
安売りしてるｱﾙな 色男さんよ｡
Looks like you're selling yourself cheap, Mr. Casanova.
異議あり！
彼女たちは皆 私の友人です!!
Objection! Those girls are all my friends.
やましい関係ではない！
Nothing more than that.
私が本気で つき合っているのは
ﾊﾂさんだけです｡
The only one I have a serious relationship with is Hatsu-san.
それとも 彼女たちと私の関係を➡
Or are you saying that you can prove my relationship with those girls?
証拠づけるものが
あるとでもいうのか!?
じゃあ 百歩 譲って➡
Okay, let's say that you are only in love with Hatsu-san.
あなたが ﾊﾂさんだけを
愛していたとしましょう｡
でも それじゃ 一方通行だ｡
But that's just one-sided.
あなたの論理で言えば
長谷川さんとﾊﾂさんが➡
According to your logic, if Hasegawa-san and Hatsu-san were still in love,
まだ愛し合っていた場合➡
あなたは
ﾊﾂさんを手に入れるため➡
then that leaves room for you to make an unlawful deal so you can make Hatsu-san yours.
不正を行う余地があることになる｡
そ… そんなことが証明できると
思っているのですか？
C-Can you even prove that?
Your honor, do you mind if I tell you a story from the past?
お奉行… 少し 昔話に
つき合ってもらえねえですかい？
(奉行)申してみよ｡
Go ahead.
昔 あるところに
仲むつまじい夫婦がいたそうです｡
Long ago, there was a very loving couple.
旦那は 下級武士の息子｡
The husband was the son of a low-class samurai
嫁さんは 高級官僚の娘｡
and the wife was the daughter of a high-ranking bureaucrat.
身分の差を反対されたが
婿入りするってことで➡
Their marriage was opposed due to their class differences,
but when the husband agreed to take the wife's last name, they were married.
何とか二人は一緒になれた｡
そんな お家柄です｡
Because he married into a good family, the husband was given a high-ranking job.
仕事も ちゃんとしたもんをと➡
旦那は 大層 立派な役職に
就かされた｡
旦那は それが気にくわなかった｡
But he didn't like it.
それは 男だったら
自分の道は自分で決めて➡
As a man, he felt he wanted to choose his own path and not be told what to do.
ﾃﾒｴの足で
歩きたいってもんでしょ｡
そこへきて 身なりも
きちんとしろってんで➡
On top of that, his wife even bought him a suit so he would look decent.
嫁さんがｽｰﾂまで
もちだしやがるもんだから➡
さすがに旦那もｷﾚて 大ｹﾞﾝｶ｡
This angered the husband and they had a huge fight.
いつもの汚ねえ着物で
初登城したそうです｡
He reported to work on his first day wearing his usual dirty kimono.
そしたら その格好を見て➡
When the conservative higher-ups saw this, they got really upset.
お堅え上の連中が
えらく怒っちまって➡
旦那は その晩
しかたなく そのｽｰﾂを着て➡
So the husband had no choice, but to put his suit on
上司の屋敷に
詫び入れに行ったんです｡
and go to his boss' house that night to apologize.
すると 自分より早く
砂利の上で土下座してる女がいる｡
There was a woman who got there before him, kneeling on the ground with her forehead on the gravel.
地面に頭こすりつけるようにして
謝る 汚ねえ格好した女がいる｡
A shabbily clothed woman apologizing with her head to the ground.
ｳﾁは これが礼装なんだって…｡
She said, in our house, this is our formal wear so please forgive my husband.
だから 旦那も勘弁してくれって
泣きながら謝る女がいたんです｡
The woman cried as she begged for forgiveness.
いつもの
きれいな着物を脱ぎ捨てて➡
His wife took off her usual pretty clothes and threw herself on the ground,
ﾃﾒｴの実家より よっぽど低い
身分の旦那の上司に➡
bowing to her husband's boss who was well beneath her social status.
頭を下げる嫁が…｡
旦那は それを見て 自分の着てた
ｽｰﾂをﾋﾞﾘﾋﾞﾘに引き裂いた｡
The husband saw this and ripped apart the suit he was wearing.
そして…｡
And...
嫁さんと一緒に 朝まで泣きながら
謝り続けたそうです｡
...along with his wife, cried and begged for forgiveness until the morning.
んなことがあってから
旦那は ここぞというときは➡
Ever since then, whenever the husband has an important event,
そのｽｰﾂで出かけるそうです｡
he always puts on that suit.
恥をしのんで謝ってくれた
嫁さんを思い出して➡
He always remembers his wife who shamelessly apologized for his sake.
ﾃﾒｴも 嫁さんのために➡
And he vows to throw away his pride and work hard for the sake of his wife.
小さいﾌﾟﾗｲﾄﾞを捨てて
がんばるように…｡
直しすぎて
すっかり丈が短くなっちまった➡
And that shabby old suit that has gone through
その ｵﾝﾎﾞﾛｽｰﾂで…｡
one too many alterations is now too short.
ﾃ… ﾃﾒｴ！ なんで その
恥ずかしいｴﾋﾟｿｰﾄﾞ 知ってんだ！
You bastard... How do you know that embarrassing story?
みっともねえから
新しいｽｰﾂ渡してくれ➡
I was asked to give you this new suit since the one you have on is so unsightly.
って言われてたんだが
すまねえな！
But sorry! He didn't wear the new suit you got for him again.
ｺｲﾂ また ｱﾝﾀの用意したｽｰﾂ
着なかったよ！
ﾊｯ！ とんでもねえ 頑固野郎だ!!
He's such a stubborn guy.
いや とんでもねえ頑固夫婦か！
No, they're just a stubborn couple.
汚ねえ格好どうし お似合いだぜ！
You're perfect for each other with those shabby clothes.
♪♪～
ﾊﾂ！ はっ…｡
Hatsu!
I will now give you your sentence.
(奉行)詮議のほどを言い渡す！
被告人 長谷川 泰三を➡
The defendant, Taizo Hasegawa...
有罪とする！
...is guilty.
You're guilty of causing your wife grief.
女房を泣かせた罪だ｡
Go after her right now. That's your sentence.
今すぐ あの女を
追ってくがいいや！
それが ｵﾒｴさんの刑だ！
Your honor!
お奉行～！
なお 破牙検事は 詳しい事情を
聞きしだい 処分を下す｡
As for Prosecutor Haga, I will hand down his punishment as soon as we get more details.
被告人が所持していた DVDは➡
The DVD owned by the defendant will be considered hazardous,
危険物とみなし
私が預かることとする！
and therefore will be left in my keeping.
(長谷川)なんでだよ！
どんだけ DVD 観てえんだよ!!
Why? You really wanna watch them, don't you?
これにて一件落着！
And with this, the case is closed.
♪♪～
なんで言わなかった？
Why didn't you say anything?
長谷川さんが以前
幕府で切腹 命じられ➡
If you had brought up the fact that Hasegawa-san ran away after being ordered to commit suicide by harakiri,
逃げたことをﾂｯこまれたら
ｵﾚたちは勝ち目はなかった｡
we would've had no chance of winning.
勝負したくなりましてね…｡
I wanted to fight.
やはり 本当に惚れた女性は➡
After all, a woman you truly love should be won over by real ability.
実力で手に入れたいものでしょ？
お前！
You...
こんなやり方しか
知らないもので➡
This is the only way I knew how.
相手にもされませんでしたがね｡
Although she never gave me the time of day,
(破牙)ｽﾃｷな女性でした｡
she was a wonderful woman.
それに ｽﾃｷな仲間も…｡
And...he has some great friends.
(破牙)うらやましい方ですね｡
How I envy him...
ﾊﾂ！ ちょっと…
ちょっと待ってくれ！
Hatsu! Wait, wait for me.
話を…｡
We need to talk... Whoa!
うおっ！
[Won the Case]
(２人)ﾊｧﾊｧ… ﾊｧﾊｧ…｡
We did it, Hasegawa-san.
やりましたね 長谷川さん！
ﾏﾀﾞｵ 報酬は ちゃんともらうから!!
Madao! We expect to get compensated!
ﾊﾂｰ！
Hatsu!
[Preview]
It suddenly appeared beneath our feet.
There was only one thing we knew.
That it was neither a living creature nor man-made.
It was despair itself.
["If You're A Man, Don't Give Up."]
[A planet is about to be destroyed by the erosion of a mysterious object.]
[The legendary savior "Umibozu" appears before those who are standing on the edge of despair.]